<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii" standalone="yes"?><darnley><location id="1" name="The Bathroom" code1="" code2="">
<text>The bathroom contains an enamelled cast iron bath with claw feet
and a toilet bearing a brass tablet calling it 'The Imperial Avenger'.
A washstand with a marble top and a pedestal washbowl complete
the ensemble. Various toileteries are scattered around in the normal
way.</text>
</location>
<location id="2" name="The Orchard" code1="" code2="">
<text>The park wall lies north and has several pear-trees trained in
espalier against it. There are a large number of apple trees, but no
fruit. There are various marks on the ground, too unclear to be sure
that they are footprints.</text>
</location>
<location id="3" name="The Kitchen Garden" code1="" code2="">
<text>The kitchen garden is full of frozen vegetables lying under snow.
Various footprints are visible in the snow.</text>
</location>
<location id="4" name="Outhouses" code1="" code2="">
<text>This section of the garden contains various outhouses; a laundry, a
coal store and a pigeon-coop.</text>
</location>
<location id="5" name="The Ornamental Pond" code1="" code2="C9">
<text>An ornamental pond stands at the western end of the terrace.
The pond is covered in ice. In the four corners of the pond are
stone pedestals. These hold statues.</text>
</location>
<location id="6" name="The Terrace" code1="" code2="">
<text>From the house a french window leads onto this paved terrace, which
shows traces of many footprints in the snow. The french window is
open and has a broken pane.</text>
</location>
<location id="7" name="Colonel Darnley's Study" code1="" code2="">
<text>Colonel Darnley's body lies on a turkish carpet in the middle of the
study. A port glass is by his body and a tantalus of port stands on a
table. The room is panelled and contains several club-chairs, some
glass cases holding stuffed birds and a writing table with a letter on
it as well as various sporting magazines and a rack of sporting guns
and pistols. As you walk on the floor by the french window in the
west wall, you feel broken glass underfoot.</text>
</location>
<location id="8" name="The Hall" code1="" code2="">
<text>The walls of the hall are decorated with swords and Civil War
armour. The floor is marble. The only furniture is a glass case
containing various flints and shards of pottery. At the far end of the
hall, two sets of fine armour stand either side of the stairs which
have barley-sugar bannisters and carved pineapple finials.</text>
</location>
<location id="9" name="The Kitchen" code1="" code2="">
<text>The kitchen has game birds hanging from the ceiling and the usual
kitchen furniture. On the sink draining-board is a knife. By the
outside door is a line of boots and some cleaning brushes and polish.</text>
</location>
<location id="10" name="Butlers' Pantry" code1="" code2="">
<text>The butlers' pantry is laid out as a sitting room with a bed behind a
curtain. Two temporary beds have been made up. There is a small
bookshelf.</text>
</location>
<location id="11" name="The Maze" code1="" code2="">
<text>Situated on the east side of the house, the maze consists of low
box hedges. The marks in the snow cannot be deciphered into
footprints.</text>
</location>
<location id="12" name="West Side of the House" code1="" code2="">
<text>The gravel path around the house passes between the smooth snow
covered tennis court and a bed of withered flowers covered in snow.
Various footprints are visible in the snow.</text>
</location>
<location id="13" name="The Lounge" code1="" code2="">
<text>The centrepiece of the lounge is a three piece suite on a Chinese
carpet. There are several tables holding magazines and novels
marked with bookmarks. Recent family portraits are on the walls.
The fireplace is carved and holds the remains of a fire. On the
mantlepiece is an Indian rosewood box with an ivory inlay.</text>
</location>
<location id="14" name="The Dining Room" code1="" code2="">
<text>The dining room holds a fine oak table with chairs in William and
Mary style. A glass case contains various pieces of Delft pottery. A
sideboard holding a silver wine cooler and a pair of Sevres porcellain
urns stand against one wall. The fireplace is of carved marble and
the walls hold various Italian landscapes.</text>
</location>
<location id="15" name="The Music Room" code1="" code2="">
<text>In the centre of the music room is a piano and, on top, a brass ashtray
with the stub of a cigar in it. There are several chairs, a music stand
and in one corner a large harp with broken strings.</text>
</location>
<location id="16" name="The Billiard Room" code1="" code2="">
<text>A full size table occupies the centre and of the wall a board indicates
the result of a game. There is a small bookcase holding magazines
and several novels by Conan Doyle and Buchan. On top of the book-
case are three wine glasses and an ashtray.</text>
</location>
<location id="17" name="The Drive" code1="" code2="">
<text>From a pair of splendid wrought iron gates the drive runs north
ending in a flight of steps leading up to the principal entrance of the
house, flanked by a pair of stone lions. The snow reveals a mass of
footprints.</text>
</location>
<location id="18" name="Avenue of Statues" code1="" code2="">
<text>This gravel path runs east-west across the front of the house flanked
by an avenue of statues. The snow covered gravel is too rough to
distinguish footprints.</text>
</location>
<location id="19" name="The Summer House" code1="" code2="">
<text>A wooden summer house stands on a patch of lawn. Inside can be
seen some croquet mallets and hoops, several cigarette ends and a
handkerchief.</text>
</location>
<location id="20" name="West Lawn" code1="" code2="">
<text>Between the summer house and the drive is a lawn. It is planted with
a few saplings and the covering of snow shows footprints.</text>
</location>
<location id="21" name="The Stables" code1="" code2="">
<text>The stables are falling into disrepair. One part contains Colonel
Darnley's bay hunter. The other garages a large Daimler. The yard
is full of straw and oil spills, and is crossed by footprints. The tack
room holds the saddle and gear for the horse.</text>
</location>
<location id="22" name="East Lawn" code1="" code2="">
<text>An area of lawn between the stables and the cottage. The smooth
covering of snow is broken by footprints.</text>
</location>
<location id="23" name="Gamekeeper's Cottage" code1="" code2="">
<text>In the damp shade of some chestnut trees is a gamekeeper's cottage
tucked against the south-east corner of the park. The door of the
cottage is open and footprints are visible across the threshold. Inside
are various items of game, two shotguns on the wall, a table covered
by oil cloth, an unmade bed, a slop-stone sink and an open fire with a
pot hanging over it. The place is very dirty; the hearth is littered
with foodscraps, the ends of cigarettes and newspapers.</text>
</location>
<location id="24" name="Milicent Darnley's Bedroom" code1="" code2="">
<text>Milicent Darnley's bedroom is decorated to a young lady's taste
with a bed, wardrobe, dressing table and a small writing table.
The surfaces are covered with small ornaments, mainly of dogs
and the walls have pictures of favourite pets.</text>
</location>
<location id="25" name="The Landing" code1="" code2="">
<text>The landing walls hold some fine antlers and animal heads and some
bad portraits of the Darnley ancestors.</text>
</location>
<location id="26" name="The Servants' Quarters" code1="" code2="">
<text>The servants' quarters consist of a single room with two single beds,
a rail for hanging clothes on behind a curtain, a wash stand and a
chest of drawers. On the chest is a bundle of correspondence and
various framed photographs. A gentleman's country-suit with a
newspaper in the pocket is hanging on the rail amongst the dresses
and a pipe is on the washstand.</text>
</location>
<location id="27" name="The Master Bedroom" code1="" code2="">
<text>Colonel and Mrs. Darnley's bedroom is heavily panelled and reflects
the Colonel's tastes, with sporting prints and a humidor of cigars.
There is a double bed, a dressing table, wardrobe and trouser press. A
small bathroom is attached.</text>
</location>
<location id="28" name="The Morning Room" code1="" code2="">
<text>The morning room holds a chintz sofa and an occasional table with
magazines and books. Against one wall is a piano. On a table stands
a gramophone. There are various pictures, mainly watercolours of
birds.</text>
</location>
<location id="29" name="Guest Room" code1="" code2="">
<text>A guest-room decorated in blue with wardrobe, bed, washstand and
writing-table. By the bed is a pair of men's slippers. On the writing
table is a pack of cigarettes and some stationary and pens.</text>
</location>
<location id="30" name="Gravel Walk" code1="" code2="">
<text>The gravel walk is covered by snow too broken to show the traces of
footprints.</text>
</location>
<location id="31" name="South-East Corner of the House" code1="" code2="">
<text>At the south-east corner of the house is a square of empty lawn. The
smooth cover of snow is broken by footprints.</text>
</location>
<person id="101" name="Colonel Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Aged 60. The Colonel served in the South African War and
contracted enteric fever which left him feeling debiliated and short-
tempered. He had only a small inheritance but made a fortune on the
stock exchange. He was free with his tips on the market, but didn't
always follow his own recommendations.</text>
</person>
<person id="102" name="Sarah Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Colonel Darnley's wife. Aged 27. Fair-haired, beautiful and
sophisticated. She wears a morning dress and shows signs of tired-
ness and stress.</text>
</person>
<person id="103" name="Millicent Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Colonel Darnley's daughter. Aged 23. Well-dressed but rather plain.
Cool and determined looking. She wears a blouse and skirt.</text>
</person>
<person id="104" name="Arthur Coniston" code1="" code2="">
<text>Millicent Darnley's fiance. Aged 25. Average height and very good
looking. His manner is honest and friendly. He dresses fashionably
and wears black patent shoes.</text>
</person>
<person id="105" name="Sir Redvers Slingsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>Friend of the deceased. Aged 52. Very tall and boney with side
whiskers and a red face. Wears country-tweeds and boots. His
manner is ill-tempered.</text>
</person>
<person id="106" name="Arnold Billingsgate" code1="" code2="">
<text>The Butler. Aged about 60; gentlemanly manners; bald and thin;
average height. Wears a tail coat and ordinary men's shoes.</text>
</person>
<person id="107" name="Mildred Goodbody" code1="" code2="">
<text>The Cook. Aged 55. Pleasant-faced. Cheerful. Overweight.</text>
</person>
<person id="108" name="Norah Bagsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>The Housemaid. Aged 19. Small pale girl who sniffs a lot. Wears a
maid's uniform.</text>
</person>
<person id="109" name="Ronald Mellors" code1="" code2="">
<text>The Gamekeeper. Stocky, black curly hair, good looking, surly-
looking. Wears working clothes and hob-nailed boots. Age 35.</text>
</person>
<item id="201" name="Pond" code1="5" code2="F2">
<text>Near the centre of the pond the ice is thinner as if it has frozen again
after having been broken. Beneath the ice you can see the missing
statue from the fourth pedestal.</text>
</item>
<item id="202" name="Sunken Statue" code1="5" code2="C30">
<text>The statue that is beneath the ice is the same as those on the
pedestals. Stuck in a crevice of the statue is the soaked butt of a
cheroot.</text>
</item>
<item id="203" name="Revolver" code1="8" code2="C8">
<text>The revolver found in the hall is a Webley-Fosbery .455 service
revolver. One bullet has been discharged from it.</text>
</item>
<item id="204" name="Statues" code1="5" code2="">
<text>The statues form a set of four, representing the Four Seasons. They
are of Italian marble and rest on their own weight rather than being
cemented to their plinths. Some strength would be required to move
one.</text>
</item>
<item id="205" name="Footprints" code1="5" code2="C25">
<text>Only one set of footprints can be made out in the snow. They are of
flat footed bootprints coming to and from the terrace.</text>
</item>
<item id="206" name="Slippers" code1="29" code2="C4">
<text>The slippers are slightly damp and stained with mud.</text>
</item>
<item id="207" name="Cigarettes" code1="29" code2="C7">
<text>These cigarettes are an expensive brand by Tribourg &amp; Freyer.</text>
</item>
<item id="208" name="Knife" code1="9" code2="C6">
<text>This kitchen knife is stained with blood.</text>
</item>
<item id="209" name="Boots" code1="9" code2="C5">
<text>All these boots are polished clean except for a mud stained pair that
apparently belong to Sir Redvers Slingsby.</text>
</item>
<item id="212" name="Footprints" code1="3" code2="C25,C27">
<text>Both flat footed boot prints and slipper prints can be seen going
between the kitchen and the maze.</text>
</item>
<item id="213" name="Bed" code1="27" code2="">
<text>This double bed has not been slept in.</text>
</item>
<item id="214" name="Wardrobe" code1="27" code2="F17">
<text>As well as clothes the wardrobe contains a selection of
men's and women's shoes.</text>
</item>
<item id="215" name="Cigars" code1="27" code2="">
<text>The cigars are Burmah cheroots.</text>
</item>
<item id="216" name="Dressing Table" code1="27" code2="">
<text>There is nothing of note on the dressing table.</text>
</item>
<item id="217" name="Shoes" code1="27" code2="C12">
<text>This selection of mens and womens shoes is unremarkable. One set of
lady's shoes is mud-stained.</text>
</item>
<item id="219" name="Correspondence" code1="26" code2="">
<text>These letters are all from Mrs. Goodbody's nephew.</text>
</item>
<item id="220" name="Photographs" code1="26" code2="">
<text>These photographs depict Mrs. Goodbody's various ugly relatives.</text>
</item>
<item id="221" name="Suit" code1="26" code2="">
<text>This gentleman's country-suit is apparently Sir Redvers'.</text>
</item>
<item id="222" name="Newspaper" code1="26" code2="C13">
<text>One headline on the front page catches your eye -
'Collapse of Rio Plata Mining Co. - Our co-respondent in Lima, Peru
reports the collapse of several silver mining companies through the
fraud of their directors. These frauds are expected to cause heavy
loss to British investors.'</text>
</item>
<item id="223" name="Pipe" code1="26" code2="">
<text>The pipe is in the style called 'calabash' with a meerschaum bowl and
amber mouthpiece.</text>
</item>
<item id="224" name="Bookshelf" code1="10" code2="">
<text>The bookshelf contains books on self-improvement and domestic
accounts.</text>
</item>
<item id="225" name="French Window" code1="6" code2="">
<text>One of the panes is smashed, but there is no glass on the terrace. The
window lock shows that it cannot be locked or unlocked from outside.</text>
</item>
<item id="226" name="Footprints" code1="6" code2="C25,C27,C28">
<text>A mess of footprints including boots, slippers and some
shoe prints.</text>
</item>
<item id="227" name="Colonel Darnley's Body" code1="7" code2="">
<text>The body is dressed in a smoking jacket open at the chest. There is a
bloody bullet wound in the front of his dress-shirt. The bullet has not
passed through the body. Evidently the Colonel had got out of his
chair on hearing or seeing his murderer. The impact of the bullet had
caused him to spin and fall and the furniture had got in the way,
further deflecting the body. It is no longer possible to tell the
direction of the shot.</text>
</item>
<item id="228" name="Port Glass" code1="7" code2="">
<text>The port glass is one of a set engraved with the words 'Floreat
Darnley'. A crust of dried liquid is at the bottom and lip marks on the
rim though no trace of lipstick.</text>
</item>
<item id="229" name="Tantalus of Port" code1="7" code2="">
<text>The tantalus is made of cherrywood. It holds an empty decanter
with a silver label marked 'Brandy' and a half full decanter marked
'Port'. The decanters are normally inaccessible since they are held in
place by a sort of 'lid' of wood which is fastened by a small lock. The
key is in the lock.</text>
</item>
<item id="230" name="Letter" code1="7" code2="C14">
<text>The letter is an incomplete draft : 'Dear Sir, I have considered your
monstrous suggestion and find I cannot....''</text>
</item>
<item id="231" name="Rack of Guns" code1="7" code2="">
<text>One of the pistols is missing from this rack.</text>
</item>
<item id="232" name="French Window" code1="7" code2="">
<text>One pane is smashed. The glass on the floor is apparently from this.</text>
</item>
<item id="233" name="Glass" code1="7" code2="">
<text>This glass is apparently from the smashed French Window.</text>
</item>
<item id="234" name="Gramophone" code1="28" code2="C10">
<text>It has a device for playing several records in sequence. All the
records are Chopin.</text>
</item>
<item id="235" name="Piano" code1="28" code2="C11">
<text>There are several sheets of Schubert Lied music on the piano's music
stand.</text>
</item>
<item id="236" name="Display Case" code1="8" code2="">
<text>According to a label at the front of the case these flints and shards of
pottery were found in the grounds of the house.</text>
</item>
<item id="237" name="Footprints" code1="12" code2="C25,C27,C28">
<text>There are slipper prints, flat-footed boot prints and some shoe prints
heading to and from the terrace and the the front of the house.</text>
</item>
<item id="238" name="Cigar Stub" code1="15" code2="">
<text>This cigar stub is a straight dark cylinder rather than the
conventional shape. That and the tarry appearance suggests a
cheroot.</text>
</item>
<item id="239" name="Piano" code1="15" code2="C11">
<text>The sheets of music on the piano are for duets.</text>
</item>
<item id="240" name="Wine Glasses" code1="16" code2="">
<text>The three wine glasses are all dirty.</text>
</item>
<item id="241" name="Ashtray" code1="16" code2="">
<text>The ashtray contains the remains of three cigars, one Havana and
two cheroots.</text>
</item>
<item id="243" name="Footprints" code1="17" code2="C25,C27,C28,C29">
<text>The prints from flat footed boots go east and west along the gravel
path in front of the house. Slipper prints come from the house and
head east and west along the path. Prints from men's shoes come
from the house and go west. Prints from lady's shoes head to and
from the frontdoor and the west lawn. At the gate end of the drive
the prints from men's hobnailed boots go between the west lawn and
the stables.</text>
</item>
<item id="244" name="Footprints" code1="31" code2="C25,C27">
<text>The prints from flat footed boots and men's slippers are visible in the
snow heading around the corner of the house, to and from the maze
and avenue of statues.</text>
</item>
<item id="245" name="Cigarette Ends" code1="19" code2="C7">
<text>These cigarette ends come from a cheap, mass produced brand.</text>
</item>
<item id="246" name="Handkerchief" code1="19" code2="C15">
<text>This is a lady's hanky, plain lace edged and perfumed.</text>
</item>
<item id="247" name="Footprints" code1="20" code2="C26,C29">
<text>Prints from lady's shoes and men's hob-nailed boots can be seen in the
snow going between the drive and the summer house.</text>
</item>
<item id="248" name="Footprints" code1="21" code2="C26">
<text>The prints from hob-nailed boots can be seen in the snow going
between the drive and the east lawn.</text>
</item>
<item id="249" name="Footprints" code1="22" code2="C26">
<text>The prints from hob-nailed boots can be seen in the snow going east
to west between the stables and the cottage.</text>
</item>
<item id="250" name="Cigarette Ends" code1="23" code2="C7">
<text>These cigarette ends come from a cheap, mass produced brand.</text>
</item>
<item id="251" name="Armour" code1="8" code2="F3">
<text>A suit of Civil War three-quarter armour with a closed helmet.
Examination discovers a revolver concealed in the helmet.</text>
</item>
<item id="252" name="Door Mat" code1="8" code2="">
<text>Some blurb about a damp doormat.</text>
</item>
<record id="300" name="What really happened at Darnley Park" code1="" code2="">
<text><p>On the morning of the murder Arthur Coniston, the boy-friend of
Milicent Darnley, arrived by arrangement to ask Colonel Darnley for
permission to marry his daughter. This conversation took place
during the afternoon and Colonel Darnley refused the request.
Although he found Coniston amusing, he felt that his visitor was
after Milicent's inheritance. Coniston, now resolved upon murder,
quietly informing the other members of the household that the
Colonel had agreed to tbe marriage. He was unaware that the Colonel
had decided to write him a letter confirming his rejection. During the
afternoon an unexpected visitor arrived, Sir Redvers Slingsby who
had invested in Peruvian mining shares on the advice of his friend
Colonel Darnley. In the morning's papers was news of the collapse of
these shares. Angry with his friend, Slingsby had rushed down to
Darnley Park to ask the Colonel to lend him money to avoid ruin.</p>
<p>Dinner that evening finished at 9.00. Milicent and Sarah retired
to the lounge for coffee while the men drank port and played
billiards. At nine 9.30 the gentlemen joined the ladies while the
servants ate in the kitchen. The atmosphere was tense since
Slingsby had not had opportunity to raise his problems. At 10.00 that
night impatience got the better of him and he drew Darnley to the
study whilst Coniston and Milicent went to the music room to sing
duets. For half an hour Slingsby and the Colonel quarelled (at this
time Billingsgate was cleaning boots in the kitchen) and at 10.30
Slingsby stormed out of the study by the hall door, slamming it
furiously. This noise was interpreted by some as a shot. The
slamming of the door underlined the generally tense atmosphere.
The ladies went upstairs but Arthur Coniston stayed in the music
room smoking a cheroot and considering his plan. He was unaware
that Sarah had plans of her own.</p>
<p>Sarah Darnley was unhappy with her husband and having an
affair with Mellors, the gamekeeper. She had arranged to meet
Mellors at the summer house at 10.45. Mellors was there, waiting and
smoking cigarettes. Sarah took steps to keep the affair secret and to
maintain to Milicent the pretence that she was in the house, she told
her of her intention to play on the morning room piano. In truth she
played a series of gramophone records which Milicent heard from her
room. It was not necessary for her to take account of Colonel Darnley
since experience had taught her that the Colonel would lock himself
in his study and get drunk on such an occasion as this. Sarah next
left the house and went down to the summer house where she met
Mellors.</p>
<p>Leaving the music room, Coniston tried the study door and finding
it locked, guessed what was happening and devised his plan. He had
stolen a gun from the study earlier in the day. He now changed into
dressing gown and slippers and went outside the house and around to
the kitchen door which was open. Reaching through the door he
picked up Sir Redvers Slingsby's boots. Changing into them he walked
around the house to the terrace. The boots being too large, they left
flat-footed bootprints. From the terrace Coniston looked into the
study where the Colonel was drinking. He tapped on the window, the
Colonel stood up and saw him, Coniston fired the gun and the Colonel
fell dead. He now had to act fast to dispose of the gun, disguise of the
fact of the bullet-hole in the window glass and return the boots. He
broke the ice on the pond with a statue taken from one of the
pedestals and threw the gun into the water. He then returned to the
kitchen, changed the boots for the slippers and then entered the
house by the front door. He did not notice Sarah who had heard the
shot and rushed back before everyone was roused by the noise and
she was discovered. In her haste Sarah dropped a handkerchief in
the summer house.</p>
<p>Coniston now came to the boldest part of his plot. He woke
Billingsgate and persuaded him to break in by the french window
instead of searching for his keys. Coniston took care to reach the
patio before his companion and threw a stone through the same pane
of glass that bore the bullet-hole from the fatal shot, thus
obliterating the evidence of from where the shooting took place. He
then invited Billingsgate to open the window and confirm that it had
been locked. He also told the Butler that he intended to follow the
murderer's bootprints which were clear in the snow. The object of
this move was to provide an explanation of the trail already left by
his slippers when he first stole and returned the boots.</p>
<p>Various minor clues led towards Coniston as the murderer, but one
was fatal to him. It was evident that the murderer had worn the
boots and returned them to the kitchen. How then had the murderer
left the kitchen in his/her own footwear? There were only two
possibilities : the murderer had left via the butlers' pantry or the
outside door. The former was impossible since three people were
occupying the pantry of whom at least one (Mrs. Goodbody) had been
wakened by the shot and would have heard any stranger entering the
room. The second was possible but the murderer would leave the foot-
prints of his ordinary footwear. Other than the boots, there were
prints only from Arthur Coniston's slippers. Coniston's explanation
that he had left these prints in following the murderers boot-trail
would not hold water. The murderer had to leave footprints in two
sets of footwear. Coniston's slippers were the only other set.</p></text>
</record>
<record id="401" name="The Sealed Room Murder" code1="" code2="">
<text><p>You have been summoned to Darnley Park one winter's day to
investigate the murder of Colonel Sebastian Darnley at some time
the previous evening.
The suspects are;
</p>
<ul> 
<li>Sarah Darnley - the deceased's wife</li>
<li>Milicent Darnley - the deceased's daughter</li>
<li>Arthur Coniston - fiance of Milicent</li>
<li>Sir Redvers Slingsby - friend of the deceased</li>
<li>Arnold Billingsgate - butler</li>
<li>Mildred Goodbody - cook</li>
<li>Norah Bagsby - housemaid</li>
<li>Ronald Mellors - gamekeeper</li>
</ul> 
<p>You are free to search the house and grounds and to question the
suspects. Examination of the scene and skillful interrogation will
yield sufficient information to solve the mystery. And mystery it is!</p>
<p>The body of Colonel Darnley was found in his study, the doors and
window of which were all locked from the inside. The only keys were
in the possession of the Colonel and his faithful butler. How could
the sealed-room murder be comitted?</p></text>
</record>
<interrogation id="1001" name="The events of yesterday" code1="" code2="">
<text><p>I married Sebastian two years ago. I am more than twenty years
younger than he - really not much older than Milicent. We have been
very happy together. Last night we all had dinner together. After-
wards the men played billiards while Milicent and I had coffee in the
lounge. At about 9.30 the men joined us for half an hour then Arthur
and Milicent said that they were going to the music room. Sebastian
and Sir Redvers had business to talk about so they went into the
study. I heard them quarelling but couldn't tell what about.
Next there was a loud noise which I took to be Sir Redvers leaving
the study by the door to the hall and banging the door. I stayed in
the lounge for ten minutes and then went upstairs where I ran into
Milicent on the landing. She said that she had left Arthur in the
billiard room and was going to bed. I went into the morning room and
played some Chopin nocturnes on the piano there until about 11.30
when I heard a noise like a shot which I thought was poachers.
Looking at my watch I decided it was time to go to bed. I was getting
changed when I heard Billingsgate rush upstairs to wake Sir Redvers.
Milicent heard the racket and came into my room from hers. And the
rest you know.</p></text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1003" name="Alibi" code1="" code2="">
<text>At 10.30 I was reading and drinking coffee in the lounge - on my
own, I'm afraid. At 11.30 I was playing the piano in the morning room
- also alone, alas! I don't suppose it looks to good?</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1004" name="These Slippers" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose slippers these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1005" name="These Boots" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1006" name="The Knife" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about the knife.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1007" name="The Cigarettes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I can't imagine why you are asking me this question. Arthur
Coniston smokes cigarettes.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1008" name="The Service Revolver" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't recognise it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1009" name="The Missing Statue" code1="" code2="">
<text>I believe a rather nasty tramp, who called two days ago threw it
into the pond.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1010" name="The Gramophone" code1="" code2="">
<text>The gramophone? I was in the morning room from about 10.40 until
11.30 playing the piano. It's possible I played a record, but I don't
remember doing so.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1011" name="The Piano" code1="" code2="">
<text>If you mean the morning room piano, I was playing it from about
10.40 until I heard the bang at 11.30. I was on my own throughout
and no-one else came into the room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1012" name="These Lady's Shoes" code1="" code2="">
<text>Yes, these are my shoes, but I don't recall when I last wore them. I
have no idea why they should be damp - possibly I had them on
earlier yesterday.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1013" name="This Newspaper" code1="" code2="">
<text>I believe that Sebastian advised one or two people to invest in
Peruvian shares.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1014" name="This Letter" code1="" code2="">
<text>My husband said something to me about having to write a letter. I
understood it was for Arthur - or was it Sir Redvers? Afterwards
Arthur told me that Sebastian had agreed to the marriage, and
Redvers said that he and Sebastian had sorted out their business; so
I'm at a loss about the letter.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1015" name="This Handkerchief" code1="" code2="">
<text>You found it in the summer house? I'm absolutely sure it isn't mine.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1016" name="Colonel Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>He was somewhat strict and suspicous by nature, but we were happy
enough.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1018" name="Milicent Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Her father spoiled her so she got used to having her own way.
Sebastian probably agreed to Arthur Coniston's proposal for fear
of what Milicent would do if he refused. I can't see him crossing
Milicent on a matter like that.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1019" name="Arthur Coniston" code1="" code2="">
<text>A charmer. I was suspicous of his motives for marrying Milicent, but
Arthur said that when he asked Sebastian my husband agreed, so I
am probably mistaken.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1020" name="Sir Redvers Slingsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>I felt he had some sort of grudge against Sebastian.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1021" name="Arnold Billingsgate" code1="" code2="">
<text>Very honest and loyal.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1022" name="Mildred Goodbody" code1="" code2="">
<text>A gossip.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1023" name="Norah Bagsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>Lazy.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1024" name="Ronald Mellors" code1="" code2="">
<text>A very loyal gamekeeper.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1025" name="Flat-footed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I'm too distressed to talk about this.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1026" name="Hob-nailed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I'm too distressed to talk about this.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1027" name="Slipper Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I'm too distressed to talk about this.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1028" name="Men's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I'm too distressed to talk about this.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1029" name="Women's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I'm too distressed to talk about this.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1030" name="The Cheroot in the Pond" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1101" name="The events of yesterday" code1="" code2="">
<text><p>Father was a difficult man to live with but I never expected - this!
Last night we all ate together until coffee which Sarah and I took
together in the lounge. The men joined us later for half an hour,
then Arthur and I went into the music room where we talked for a
while and played duets on the piano. At about 10.30 I decided to go to
bed. I know the time because I looked at my watch when there was a
loud noise - probably a poacher somewhere. Arthur stayed in the
billiard room and I went upstairs.
I think I saw Sir Redvers disappearing into his bedroom, but I was
distracted by Sarah who was on the landing. She said she was
intending to play the piano in the morning room and hoped it would't
disturb me. I went to my room and stayed there. I heard Sarah
playing the piano then drifted off to sleep. I woke up at about 11.20
by the bedside clock and heard Sarah still playing a Chopin nocturne.
She seemed to be having trouble since the same part was being
repeated over and over again. I went to sleep for a few more minutes
when there was a bang - a door slamming, I thought. Then at about
midnight there was a racket of people everywhere. I went into
Sarah's room and found her undressing there. We went into the
morning room and found Billingsgate waking Sir Redvers.</p></text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1103" name="Alibi" code1="" code2="">
<text>I was with Arthur in the music room at 10.30 and, naturally, I was
alone in bed at 11.30.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1104" name="These Slippers" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose slippers these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1105" name="These Boots" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about these boots.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1106" name="The Knife" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about the knife.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1107" name="The Cigarettes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't smoke. My father smoked cigars.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1108" name="This Service Revolver" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't recognise it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1109" name="The Missing Statue" code1="" code2="">
<text>Someone - I forget who - told me that a beggar had pushed it into the
pond. Out of spite I suppose.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1110" name="The Gramophone" code1="" code2="">
<text>We have a gramophone in the morning room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1111" name="The Piano" code1="" code2="">
<text>Which piano? Arthur and I played duets on the music room piano for
a while after dinner. I remember that later, Sarah said she intended
to play the morning room piano. I woke up at about 11.20 and heard
Sarah still playing a Chopin nocturne. She was having difficulty
and repeated the same piece again and again.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1112" name="These Lady's Shoes" code1="" code2="">
<text>They aren't my shoes.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1113" name="This Newspaper" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't read the newspaper frequently.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1114" name="This Letter" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about this letter.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1115" name="This Handkerchief" code1="" code2="">
<text>I'm always losing handkerchiefs so I suppose it could be mine. I don't
remember when I lose them. I certainly wasn't in the summer house
yesterday. Is it important?</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1116" name="Colonel Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Daddy was a tyrant but always kind to me. He was always fearful
that Sarah would leaver him for a younger man.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1117" name="Sarah Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>We got on well enough though it is difficult to have a step-mother
who is almost the same age. I thought she would leave daddy some
day as soon as she found a lover. But, of course, she would need
Daddy's money.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1119" name="Arthur Coniston" code1="" code2="">
<text>He's a darling! I don't know how he persuaded daddy to agree, so I
am probably mistaken.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1120" name="Sir Redvers Slingsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>I didn't know him before last night.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1121" name="Arnold Billingsgate" code1="" code2="">
<text>A decent old fellow.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1122" name="Mildred Goodbody" code1="" code2="">
<text>An old dear.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1123" name="Norah Bagsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>A clumsy girl.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1124" name="Ronald Mellors" code1="" code2="">
<text>Furtive. I don't like the way he looks at my step-mother. I advised
Daddy to get rid of him.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1125" name="Flat-footed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>Oh really, it's too silly to ask me to recognise footprints.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1126" name="Hob-nailed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>Oh really, it's too silly to ask me to recognise footprints.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1127" name="Slipper Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>Oh really, it's too silly to ask me to recognise footprints.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1128" name="Men's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>Oh really, it's too silly to ask me to recognise footprints.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1129" name="Women's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>Oh really, it's too silly to ask me to recognise footprints.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1130" name="The Cheroot in the Pond" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1201" name="The events of yesterday" code1="" code2="">
<text><p>I was down for the weekend. It was no secret that I was going to
ask Colonel Darnley for permission to marry Milicent. I popped the
question to the old boy in the afternoon and he agreed. Last night we
all had dinner together and afterwards we fellows played a little
billiards before joining the ladies for coffee. At about 10.00 Sir
Redvers broke up the party by asking Darnley to go into the study
with him. I asked Milicent to come with me to the music room where
we played duets for half an hour. There was a noise. Milicent
thought it was a poacher and hoped that Mellor's would catch him.
She decided to go to bed. I stayed on to smoke a cigar and didn't go up
until 11.00. I noticed nothing odd except that to get to my bedroom I
had to go through the morning room where the gramophone was
playing a Chopin nocturne but there was no-one there. I undressed
and went to bed but couldn't sleep. At about 11.30 I heard a noise -
a door banging, so I thought at the time. I decided to go downstairs
and smoke another cigar in the lounge. I noticed a light under the
study door and knocked on it to see who was there. I got worried
when it was locked and no-one answered so I got Billingsgate and
together we went outside and round to the french window. It was
locked too, so I picked a stone up and broke the glass. Billingsgate
stuck his hand through the hole and tried the lock. He told me it was
locked on the inside, and - damn me! - he was right. We both went
inside and found Darnley on the floor, shot and dead. When we
checked the doors to the hall and lounge we found the Colonel's keys
in the locks, so it would have been impossible to open them from the
outside. I had noticed some bootprints outside, so I went out and
followed them. They led around the house to the kitchen door. I
followed in my slippers.</p></text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1203" name="Alibi" code1="" code2="">
<text>Milicent and I were together in the music room at 10.30. I don't
know how anyone can be expected to have an alibi for 11.30.
Certainly a single gentleman could never admit to one, if you follow
my meaning.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1204" name="These Slippers" code1="" code2="">
<text>These are my slippers. I was wearing them when Billingsgate and I
broke into the study.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1205" name="These Boots" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about the boots.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1206" name="The Knife" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about the knife.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1207" name="The Cigarettes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I smoke and expensive cigarette made by Fribourg &amp; Treyer in
London - those and cigars after dinner, Cheroots same as old Darnley.
I would never smoke cheap cigarettes.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1208" name="This Service Revolver" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't recognise it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1209" name="The Missing Statue" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know what you're talking about.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1210" name="The Gramophone" code1="" code2="">
<text>When I went to bed at 11.00, the gramophone was playing a Chopin
nocturne. Otherwise the morning room was empty. Later the record
appeared to be stuck. It was still playing when I went downstairs
shortly after 11.30.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1211" name="The Piano" code1="" code2="">
<text>After dinner Milicent and I played duets on the piano in the music
room. Ah - now that I remember, there is also a piano in the morning
room, but on the couple of occasions I went into the room there was
no-one there, just a gramophone playing.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1212" name="These Lady's Shoes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose shoes these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1213" name="This Newspaper" code1="" code2="">
<text>I heard that old Slingsby had plunged into mining shares and needed
money urgently. Colonel Darnley mentioned it to me during our
conversation.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1214" name="This Letter" code1="" code2="">
<text>I have no idea who old Darnley was writing to. I suppose it could
have been to old Slingsby. I fancy he had lost a lot of money and
needed a loan. We had spoken in the afternoon and Darnley had
agreed that I could marry Milicent.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1215" name="This Handkerchief" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose handkerchief it is.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1216" name="Colonel Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>A decent old buffer. When I asked his permission to marry Milicent
he agreed straight away. I was suprised, I admit it!</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1217" name="Sarah Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Very lively. I couldn't see old Darnley hanging on to her.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1218" name="Milicent Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Be a gentleman, old fellow! Don't ask me to criticise my future wife.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1220" name="Sir Redvers Slingsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>I scarcely know him but he seemed very angry with Darnley about
something. I got the feeling he had money troubles. A dangerous
fellow I should think.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1221" name="Arnold Billingsgate" code1="" code2="">
<text>I barely know the chap.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1222" name="Mildred Goodbody" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know the woman.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1223" name="Norah Bagsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know the girl.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1224" name="Ronald Mellors" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know the chap.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1225" name="Flat-footed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I followed the Bootprints from the terrace around to the kitchen.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1226" name="Hob-nailed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose they are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1227" name="Slipper Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>The prints from the slippers are mine.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1228" name="Men's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I think they are probably Billingsgate's.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1229" name="Women's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1230" name="The Cheroot in the Pond" code1="" code2="">
<text>I suppose it could be mine. I fancy I was smoking when Billingsgate
and I went outside. Maybe I did throw it in the pond. Does it matter?</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1301" name="The events of yesterday" code1="" code2="">
<text><p>I have known Darnley for about 20 years. It was some confidential
business dealings that brought me here urgently yesterday. Last
night I had dinner with the family and young Coniston.</p>
<p>Afterwards about 9.00 - we gentlemen had a game and some port
in the billiard room, then we joined the ladies in the lounge for half an
hour. Darnley and I left the others at 10.00 and chatted about our
business for a while. The discussion was very friendly and I left
Darnley alive at 10.30. I was sleeping in the servants quarters and
went to bed straight away. Having had a bit to drink I slept very
soundly and heard nothing until Billingsgate woke me at midnight to
tell me about this terrible business.</p></text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1303" name="Alibi" code1="" code2="">
<text>I left Darnley alive at 10.30 and it's damn nonsense to suggest I
shot him with all the house awake and then waited to see what would
happen. At 11.30 I was asleep like a good Christian, and the Devil
take you if a fellow needs an alibi!</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1304" name="These Slippers" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose slippers these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1305" name="These Boots" code1="" code2="">
<text>These are certainly my boots. I last wore them yesterday afternoon
and put them out for Billingsgate to clean. I certainly didn't wear
them after dinner and can't explain who may have. I suppose that,
if the staff were asleep, someone could have sneaked into the
kitchen and taken them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1306" name="The Knife" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about the knife.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1307" name="The Cigarettes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I smoke a pipe and the occasional Havana cigar. My pipe is in my
room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1308" name="This Service Revolver" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't recognise it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1309" name="The Missing Statue" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know what you're talking about.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1310" name="The Gramophone" code1="" code2="">
<text>The Darnley's have a gramophone in the morning room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1311" name="The Piano" code1="" code2="">
<text>The Darnley's have two pianos, one in the music room and one in the
morning room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1312" name="These Lady's Shoes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose shoes these are. </text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1313" name="This Newspaper" code1="" code2="">
<text>I was reading it on the train coming here. Some of my friends lost
money in the collapse.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1314" name="This Letter" code1="" code2="">
<text>The letter certainly wasn't addressed to me. Darnley would have
called me by name, not 'Dear Sir' - afterall we were friends.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1315" name="This Handkerchief" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose handkerchief it is.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1316" name="Colonel Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>A hard man but very fair. Once I had explained my business problem
he agreed to help me out.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1317" name="Sarah Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Darnley should never have married her.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1318" name="Milicent Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>A charming young lady. Spoiled by her father. Personally I shouldn't
like to get on her wrong side.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1319" name="Arthur Coniston" code1="" code2="">
<text>Last night was the first time I met him but he seemed a decent
fellow.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1321" name="Arnold Billingsgate" code1="" code2="">
<text>I barely know the man.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1322" name="Mildred Goodbody" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know the woman.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1323" name="Norah Bagsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know the girl.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1324" name="Ronald Mellors" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know the man.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1325" name="Flat-footed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>The bootprints around the house look like mine, but I didn't make
them. I'm not flat-footed.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1326" name="Hob-nailed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1327" name="Slipper Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1328" name="Men's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1329" name="Women's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1330" name="The Cheroot in the Pond" code1="" code2="">
<text>A cheroot? Not me, old man! I'm one for Havanas if I'm not smoking
the old pipe.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1401" name="The events of yesterday" code1="" code2="">
<text><p>I have worked for the Darnley family since I was a boy. Colonel
Darnley was a very honest, decent gentleman. Last night I waited on
the guests at dinner. There was the family, Sir Redvers and Mr.
Coniston. Afterwards I served port to the gentlemen in the billiard
room. I had my own dinner at 9.30 with the other servants, then
cleaned boots. I was disturbed by a loud bang at 10.30. I thought it
was a door so did nothing about it. Shortly afterwards I went to bed
in the butlers' pantry and was woken by Mr. Coniston at 11.30.</p>
<p>He said that he had not been able to sleep and had gone to the
lounge to smoke. He saw a light under the study doors and was
concerned because the doors were locked and Colonel Darnley would
not answer. I offered to get my own keys but Mr. Coniston said it was
too urgent. As far as the study is concerned the Colonel kept the
keys on his person and I keep mine hidden - I won't say where - but
you can be sure no-one can get their on hand either. We left through
the kitchen door and I walked round to the french windows, Mr.
Coniston ran and was there a couple of seconds before me. He threw
a stone through the window and one of us, me I think put his hand
through the hole to open the lock. I can confirm that the window
was locked. We both went into the room and saw the Colonel's body
with a bullet through the chest. The body was on the floor and you
couldn't tell where the shot had come from. The Colonel's keys were
in the locks of the two doors.</p></text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1403" name="Alibi" code1="" code2="">
<text>I was with Mrs. Goodbody and young Norah in my pantry at both
10.30 and 11.30.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1404" name="These Slippers" code1="" code2="">
<text>I believe these are Mr. Coniston's slippers. He was wearing them
when he woke me up to help the Colonel.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1405" name="These Boots" code1="" code2="">
<text>The boots belong to Sir Redvers. They are - shall we say - on the
large side? He gave them to me yesterday afternoon and I cleaned
them after dinner. They were in the kitchen until I cleaned them. I
suppose they might have been taken afterwards. I don't think
anyone could have slipped past us servants to get to the kitchen
through my pantry. What puzzles me is : if a boot thief came in from
the outside door, what on earth was he wearing on his feet?</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1406" name="The Knife" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about the knife.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1407" name="The Cigarettes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't smoke. Colonel Darnley smoked cigars.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1408" name="This Service Revolver" code1="" code2="">
<text>It belongs to the master and was kept in the study. The study is
normally unlocked and it could have been removed at any time.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1409" name="The Missing Statue" code1="" code2="">
<text>Mr. Mellors told me that a tramp pitched it into the pond two days
ago.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1410" name="The Gramophone" code1="" code2="">
<text>There is a gramophone in the morning room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1411" name="The Piano" code1="" code2="">
<text>There are two pianos, one in the music room and the other in the
morning room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1412" name="These Lady's Shoes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I'm not sure. They may be Mrs. Sarah's or Miss Milicent's.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1413" name="This Newspaper" code1="" code2="">
<text>I'm afraid I don't recognise it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1414" name="This Letter" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1415" name="This Handkerchief" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1416" name="Colonel Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>The master was extremely good to his family.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1417" name="Sarah Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't believe it is proper to speak of the family.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1418" name="Milicent Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't believe it is proper to speak of the family.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1419" name="Arthur Coniston" code1="" code2="">
<text>I scarcely know the gentleman.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1420" name="Sir Redvers Slingsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>I've met the gentleman once or twice. A very hot-tempered man.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1422" name="Mildred Goodbody" code1="" code2="">
<text>A fine woman. Honest as the day is long.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1423" name="Norah Bagsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>A decent-enough girl. A little lazy.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1424" name="Ronald Mellors" code1="" code2="">
<text>He's the gamekeeper. He seems honest enough.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1425" name="Flat-footed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I've studied all the people here and none of them are flat-footed. It's
a mystery ro me why the bootprints should be flat-footed.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1426" name="Hob-nailed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1427" name="Flat-footed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I believe the slipper prints are Mr. Coniston's.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1428" name="Men's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>The shoe prints are mine.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1429" name="Women's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1430" name="The Cheroot in the Pond" code1="" code2="">
<text>As far as I'm aware only the Colonel smoked cheroots. But he was a
most particular man and would never throw a butt into the pond.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1501" name="The events of yesterday" code1="" code2="">
<text><p>I have worked here for five years. Last night I cooked and
washed up with Norah. At about 10.30 I heard a loud bang, it gave
me quite a shock. Not long after we went to bed; me and Norah behind
the curtain and Mr. B. on the other side. We had to muck in with Mr.
B. because Sir Redvers had turned up unexpectedly and taken our
room. I was woke up by a shot at 11.20 (according to my clock); the
others was still asleep. I didn't bother 'cos I thought it was poachers.
A few minutes later Mr. Coniston turned up in his dressing gown and
slippers and woke up Mr. B. but I couldn't hear what it was about.</p></text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1503" name="Alibi" code1="" code2="">
<text>We was all three together, me, Norah and Mr. B. in Mr. B.'s pantry at
10.30 and 11.30. Of course we was asleep at 11.30 so I suppose any of
us could have slipped out without the others noticing.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1504" name="These Slippers" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose slippers these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1505" name="These Boots" code1="" code2="">
<text>I remember Billingsgate cleaning boots after dinner but I can't swear
that Sir Redvers' boots were among them. Anyone could have taken
the foots from the kitchen if they came in from the outside door. All
the outside doors are left open since we live in the country.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1506" name="The Knife" code1="" code2="">
<text>I used that knife to skin a hare, which explains the blood.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1507" name="The Cigarettes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't smoke. Colonel Darnley smoked cigars.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1508" name="This Service Revolver" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1509" name="The Missing Statue" code1="" code2="">
<text>Mr. B. told me a tramp threw it into the pond. There was a smelly old
villain came by a couple of days ago.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1510" name="The Gramophone" code1="" code2="">
<text>There is a gramophone in the morning room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1511" name="The Piano" code1="" code2="">
<text>There are two pianos, one in the music room and the other in the
morning room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1512" name="These Lady's Shoes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I'm not sure. They may be Mrs. Sarah's or Miss Milicent's.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1513" name="This Newspaper" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't have time to read the paper.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1514" name="This Letter" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1515" name="This Handkerchief" code1="" code2="">
<text>Mrs. Sarah and Miss Milicent both have handkerchief's like this one.
I can't say whose it is.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1516" name="Colonel Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>A hard man both in his business dealings and with his family.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1517" name="Sarah Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Far too young to have married the Colonel and not very happy.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1518" name="Milicent Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Not a young woman I should want to cross.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1519" name="Arthur Coniston" code1="" code2="">
<text>What a charmer! I always thought he was after Miss Milicent's
money, but the Colonel obviously didn't.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1520" name="Sir Redvers Slingsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>I believe he was very cross with the Colonel about some business
dealings.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1521" name="Arnold Billingsgate" code1="" code2="">
<text>A gentleman. Very loyal to Colonel Darnley.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1523" name="Norah Bagsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>A good girl but lazy.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1524" name="Ronald Mellors" code1="" code2="">
<text>Not a nice man. Not to be trusted. Colonel Darnley talked of giving
him his notice; he'd already given him a warning letter.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1525" name="Flat-footed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I remember the gardener's child playing around wearing grown-up's
boots. They made flat-footed prints because they were too big for
her.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1526" name="Hob-nailed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1527" name="Slipper Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1528" name="Men's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1529" name="Women's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1530" name="The Cheroot in the Pond" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1601" name="The events of yesterday" code1="" code2="">
<text><p>I have worked here for six months and I don't like it. Last night I
helped Mrs. Goodbody to prepare dinner and afterwards I served
coffee in the lounge to Mrs. Sarah and Miss. Milicent. Then I helped
Mrs. G. to wash up whilst Mr. Billingsgate cleaned the boots. Just
before we went to bed there was a loud bang. I thought it was a shot
but Mrs. G. said it was a door banging. Then we went to bed. Mrs. G.
and I had to sleep behind a curtain in the butlers' pantry 'cos Sir
Redvers had come unexpectedly and taken our room. Last thing was
I woke when Mr. Coniston woke Mr. B, but I stayed where I was.</p></text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1603" name="Alibi" code1="" code2="">
<text>I'm not good where times are concerned. I s'pose I was with Mr. B.
and Mrs. G. in Mr. B.'s room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1604" name="These Slippers" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose slippers these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1605" name="These Boots" code1="" code2="">
<text>Mr. B. cleaned boots after dinner.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1606" name="The Knife" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about the knife.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1607" name="The Cigarettes" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't smoke. Colonel Darnley smoked cigars.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1608" name="This Service Revolver" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1609" name="The Missing Statue" code1="" code2="">
<text>I wasn't aware it was missing.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1610" name="The Gramophone" code1="" code2="">
<text>There is a gramophone in the morning room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1611" name="The Piano" code1="" code2="">
<text>There are two pianos, one in the music room and the other in the
morning room.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1612" name="These Lady's Shoes" code1="" code2="">
<text>These are Mrs. Sarah's shoes. i don't know when they were last worn.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1613" name="This newspaper" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1614" name="This Letter" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1615" name="This Handkerchief" code1="" code2="">
<text>Both the ladies have this sort of hanky. Sometimes mrs. G. is given
the older ones.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1616" name="Colonel Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>Very strict. I didn't like him.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1617" name="Sarah Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>If you ask me she didn't like the Colonel. He was too old for her.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1618" name="Milicent Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>A determined young woman. It's lucky for the Colonel that he agreed
to less Miss. Milicent marry Mr. Coniston.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1619" name="Arthur Coniston" code1="" code2="">
<text>A very nice gentleman. I'm suprised the Colonel liked him.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1620" name="Sir Redvers Slingsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>I didn't know the gentleman.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1621" name="Arnold Billingsgate" code1="" code2="">
<text>An old fuddy-duddy.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1622" name="Mildred Goodbody" code1="" code2="">
<text>Very kind to me.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1624" name="Ronald Mellors" code1="" code2="">
<text>A rough man. A womanizer by all accounts.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1625" name="Flat-footed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1626" name="Hob-nailed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1627" name="Slipper Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1628" name="Men's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1629" name="Women's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1630" name="The Cheroot in the Pond" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1701" name="Ronald Mellor's Statement" code1="" code2="">
<text><p>I have worked for Colonel Darnley for five years. He was strict
but fair. I have no complaints. Last night I did my last rounds at
8.00 pm. I saw nothing suspicious. I spent the rest of the evening at
home and went to bed at 10.00. I didn't hear any strange noises. It
wasn't the weather for poachers.</p></text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1703" name="Alibi" code1="" code2="">
<text>I was in my cottage alone all evening and I don't gave a tinker's
curse if you believe me or not. If you look for my tracks to the big
house. you won't find them.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1704" name="These Slippers" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't give a damn about slippers.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1705" name="These Boots" code1="" code2="">
<text>Piss off! I'm not showing anyone my boots.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1706" name="The Knife" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about any bloody knife!</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1707" name="The Cigarettes" code1="" code2="">
<text>Go to hell! I'm not answering any questions.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1708" name="This Service Revolver" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't own a revolver, I use a shotgun.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1709" name="The Missing Statue" code1="" code2="">
<text>Mrs. G. at the big house turned away a tramp. That'd be two days
ago. I caught him lurking about and found the statue in the pond.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1710" name="The Gramophone" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about any gramophone.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1711" name="The Piano" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about any bloody piano.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1712" name="These Lady's Shoes" code1="" code2="">
<text>Do I look like I wear lady's shoes?</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1713" name="This Newspaper" code1="" code2="">
<text>I only ever read the racing pages.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1714" name="This Letter" code1="" code2="">
<text>Why should I know anything about some bloody letter?</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1715" name="This Handkerchief" code1="" code2="">
<text>Do I look like I use lady's hankys?</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1716" name="Colonel Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>I've nothing to say.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1717" name="Sarah Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>I've nothing to say.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1718" name="Milicent Darnley" code1="" code2="">
<text>I've nothing to say.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1719" name="Arthur Coniston" code1="" code2="">
<text>I've nothing to say.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1720" name="Sir Redvers Slingsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>I've nothing to say.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1721" name="Arnold Billingsgate" code1="" code2="">
<text>I've nothing to say.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1722" name="Mildred Goodbody" code1="" code2="">
<text>I've nothing to say.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1723" name="Norah Bagsby" code1="" code2="">
<text>I've nothing to say.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1725" name="Flat-footed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>Clear off! I'm not showing anyone my boots.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1726" name="Hob-nailed Bootprints" code1="" code2="">
<text>Clear off! I'm not showing anyone my boots.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1727" name="Slipper Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose they are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1728" name="Men's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know whose these are.</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1729" name="Women's Shoe Prints" code1="" code2="">
<text>Do I look like I wear women's shoes?</text>
</interrogation>
<interrogation id="1730" name="The Cheroot in the Pond" code1="" code2="">
<text>I don't know anything about it.</text>
</interrogation>
</darnley>